<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/css" href="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/code/pfs.css"?><TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>An ordinance of the Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament for the explanation of a former ordinance for the taking and receiving of the accompts of the kingdom.</title>
            <title>Laws, etc.</title>
            <author>England and Wales.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 6KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 5 1-bit group-IV TIFF page images.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2016-02">2016-02 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B22141</idno><idno type="EEBO-CITATION">12098961</idno>
  <idno type="VID">196791</idno>
  <idno type="EEBO-PROQUEST">2240947170</idno>
  
            <idno type="STC">Wing E1977</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">12098961</idno>
            <availability><p>This keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above is co-owned by the
    institutions providing financial support to the Early English Books Online Text Creation
    Partnership. This text is available for reuse, according to the terms of <ref target="https://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/"> Creative Commons 0 1.0 Universal
    licence</ref>. The text can be copied, modified, distributed and performed, even for commercial
    purposes, all without asking permission.</p></availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online text creation partnership.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt><relatedItem type="facs" target="https://data.historicaltexts.jisc.ac.uk/view?pubId=eebo-e"/>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B22141)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 196791)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English books, 1641-1700 ; 237:E54, no 22)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>An ordinance of the Lords and Commons assembled in Parliament for the explanation of a former ordinance for the taking and receiving of the accompts of the kingdom.</title>
                  <title>Laws, etc.</title>
                  <author>England and Wales.</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>[2], 8 p.   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed for Edward Husbands,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>London :</pubPlace>
                  <date>Iuly 11, 1644.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in Thomason Collection, British Library.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,363 texts created during Phase 1 of the project have been released into the public domain as of 1 January 2015. Anyone can now take and use these texts for their own purposes, but we respectfully request that due credit and attribution is given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Full documentation of the original data capture process is available from the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.
   All versions of the texts are now archived and freely available for download. See <ref target="https://textcreationpartnership.org/faq/#faq05">the TCP Download FAQ</ref>
   for detailed information. The TEI P5 versions are also freely available from the <ref target="https://github.com/textcreationpartnership">TCP Github repository</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp" matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)" replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char" matchPattern="(.+)" replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term type="topical_term">Finance, Public --  Great Britain --  To 1688.</term>
               <term type="geographic_name">Great Britain --  History --  Civil War, 1642-1649 --  Sources.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2014-02 </date>
            <label>Apex CoVantage</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen </label>Sampled and proofread </change>
         <change>
            <date>2014-03 </date>
            <label>Kate Allen</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited </change>
         <change>
            <date>2015-03 </date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion </change>
      <change><date>2021-05 </date><label>lb</label>TEI P5 conversion </change></revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <front>
         <div type="title_page">
            <pb facs="tcp:196791:1"/>
            <p> AN ORDINANCE OF THE Lords and Commons Assembled in PARLIAMENT, FOR THE EXPLANATION OF A former Ordinance for the Taking and Receiving of the ACCOMPTS OF THE KINGDOM.</p>
            <q>
               <floatingText xml:lang="eng">
                  <body>
                     <div type="license">
                        <p>ORdered by the Commons in Parliament, That this Ordinance be forthwith printed &amp; published:</p>
                        <closer>
                           <signed>Henry Elsyng, Cler. Parl. D. Com.</signed>
                        </closer>
                     </div>
                  </body>
               </floatingText>
            </q>
            <p>
               <hi>London,</hi> Printed for <hi>Edward Husbands,</hi> Iuly 11. 1644.</p>
            <pb facs="tcp:196791:2"/>
         </div>
      </front>
      <body>
         <div type="ordinance">
            <pb n="3" facs="tcp:196791:2"/>
            <head>
               <hi>An Ordinance of the <hi>Lords</hi> and <hi>Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mons</hi> in Parliament assembled, for the Explanation of a former Ordinance for the taking and receiving the Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compts of the Kingdom.</hi>
            </head>
            <p>WHereas upon the former Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance of both Houses of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament, for taking the Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compts of the Kingdom, some doubt doth arise, whether there be sufficient power given the Committee named in that Ordinance, by the expresse words thereof, to determine any Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compts by them taken, and to receive and keep the Vouchers which concern the same Accompts; And whereas the Subcommittees to be appointed by them by vertue of the said Ordinance,
<pb n="4" facs="tcp:196791:3"/> in any County, City, or place where they shall think meet, have the self<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>same power given them within their severall limits as the said Committee hath, and are not appointed to receive any directions from, or to return any Accompts unto them, which will prove inconvenient, and hinder the orderly taking of the said Accompts by the said Committee.</p>
            <p>Be it therefore Ordained by the Lords and Commons in Parliament, That the said Committee or any five or more of them, shall have power and authority to determine the Accompts by them taken, to give discharges in writings under the hands of any five or more of them, and to receive and keep all Vouchers which concern the same; And that all and every Subcommittees, appointed or to be appointed by vertue of the said Ordi<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nance, shall pursue such directions as they shall from time to time receive from the said Cōmittee of Accompts,
<pb n="5" facs="tcp:196791:3"/> for the better ordering and expediting of their Accompts, and likewise to re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>turn unto them all and singular Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compts which shall be taken by them before the same shall be finally deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined. And because a true Accompt cannot be taken, of such Monies as are payed unto the Armies Officers, and Souldiers in the severall Garri<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons, Cities and Counties of the Kingdom, except exact Musters be duly made and kept of the said Forces, and accompts taken of the Arms and Horse in the severall Counties afore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>said; It is hereby further Ordained, That the severall Committees of Parliament, or such or so many of them as have power to execute the se<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>verall Ordinances in the said Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Cities and Garrisons, shall from time to time hereafter, every moneth at the least, or oftner if they shall see cause, take particular Musters, and keep true Muster Rolls of all the Officers and Souldiers by
<pb n="6" facs="tcp:196791:4"/> name now being, or hereafter to be raised within the said severall Coun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ties, Cities and Garrisons where they are authorised as Committees of Parliament; and that all Colonells, Captaines, and Officers within the said Armies, Counties, Cities, and Garrisons raised or to be raised, shall from time to time make good all Hor<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ses and Armes under their severall Commands, unto the said severall Committees of Parliament, in the said severall Counties, Cities, and Garrisons aforesaid, unlesse the same were lost in actuall service; and the said severall Committees of Par<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>liament shall returne the said Muster Rolls, or true notes of all the Musters aforesaid, and certifie all the defects therein, and of Armes and Horse aforesaid unto the Commit<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tee for the accompts of the Kingdom, or unto the several Sub-Committees of accompts in the severall Counties of the Kingdom, which the same Sub-Committees
<pb n="7" facs="tcp:196791:4"/> shall return up unto the said Committee of accompts in man<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ner and form aforesaid, to the end that satisfaction may be made unto the Cōmon-wealth for such losse of Horse and Armes out of the said Officers pay. And that all Fines to be imposed by vertue of the said Ordinance of Ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>compts, and all such summes of mony as the said Committee of Accompts, or any two of them shall certifie to be due, and owing by any Person or Per<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>sons upon their said accompts deter<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mined by them, shall be payed into the Chamber of <hi>London,</hi> and shall not be issued out but by Orders of both Hou<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ses; which Orders shal be first entred with the said Committee of accompts before any money be payed upon the same, other then <gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>re<gap reason="illegible" resp="#murp" extent="2 letters">
                  <desc>••</desc>
               </gap>s of such mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>nies as by particular Acts of Parlia<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ment, and Ordinances, are limited to particular Treasurers, nominated in the said Acts of Parliament, and Ordinances which shall be payed into
<pb n="8" facs="tcp:196791:5"/> the said Treasurers. And be it further Ordained by the Authority aforesaid, that such summe and summes of mo<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ney as the said Committee, or any five of them shall find necessary for the pay<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ing and satisfying of the Registers, Accomptants, Clerkes, Agents, and Ministers imployed by them or other<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>wise, for defraying any Charges for taking the said Accompts, shall be payed out of the Chamber of <hi>London</hi> a<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>foresaid, whensoever the said Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee or any five of them shall require the same, for which they shall keep and give a true and perfect accompt under their Hands in writing, and that ac<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>cording to an Order of the thirteenth of March, two hundred pound shall be forthwith payed unto the said Com<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>mittee for Accompts.</p>
            <trailer>FINIS.</trailer>
         </div>
      </body>
   </text>
</TEI>